# Abhinav Kumar

TORONTO, M2J1L3 | 437-989-9869 | abhinavdogra649@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/abhinav-dogra-22b44016a | https://github.com/Money2Code/Myportfolio

#### **PROFILE**

Successfully finished more than three years of Python development with experience in coding, testing, and web development using the Django framework. Consequently, using Python-based functionality to manipulate data and consume APIs. Additionally, if you are proficient in a variety of Python libraries, cooperative education is the ideal way to begin your career in cloud engineering. Integrating cloud computing into a career will improve working in both environments engaging in critical thought will therefore enable to work efficiently.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

Logical approach | Business communication | Aptitude | Team Working | Python | Django | Regression | JSON | Docker | Jenkins | VSCode | Postman | Git | Sonar | Checkmarx | Vault | Sentry | Python | Pytest | CSV | BeautifulSoup | Linux | Html | CSS | Vagrant | Azure | VMware | Oracle virtualbox

## **EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS**

Ontario College Graduate Certificate in Cloud Computing
 Loyalist College, Toronto Canada
Bachelor's Degree Computer Science
 Chandigarh University , Mohali India

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER-II | BAJAJ MARKETS**

01/2023-02/2023

- Sprint Planning with a Mutual fund Team .
- Development for the payment and stock-exchange portal as well as Testing and Go-live planning.
- Successfully deployment of mutual funds portal for live customers.
- Critical approach towards the portal to develop api for stock holding.
- Worked as team lead for backend developers.

# ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | COGNIZANT

06/2019-12/2022

## Network LEC B2B.(https://www.kpn.com/)

- Developed Python partition which is whole isolated platform to consume the API, which was developed in java and connected to the partition through Python services model
- Provided a whole new URL for fetching the data after serialization as well as the OOPs concept of Python.
- Statistical analysis on data by performing sonar on the code using different Jenkins stages in order to run the Python code through these stages.
- Improved the code coverage to 94 % by implementing the logic's and by reducing the redundancy.
- Achieved a most effective code for the platform in bitbucket.

## WHG( wyndham hospitality)

Developed python api for payload for hotel reservations

- Worked on a mock test with the pytest library.
- Deployed a platform which collects data of new customers.
- Successfully achieved less complexity and high code coverage.

## **CO-OP Software Developer Intern at Cognizant**

01/2019-04/2019

- Developed the Health management system in python.
- Front End development using angular for portal.
- Lead the team of four members during the project.

#### **PROMOTIONS**

- Programmer analyst to software Developer
- Software Developer to associate Developer

## **COURSE & CERTIFICATION**

- Python boot camp course Udemy 2020
- Devops complete hands on by udemy 2023
- FSE certified by Cognizant.
- Cloud certification (Azure104) expected by JAN 2024

#### **INTERESTS & EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

- Hacker rank certificate(<u>https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/f6579c8bc3de</u>)
- Clouds and Devops
- Gym and fitness training
- Secured Second position at King kong naturals (Bodybuilding)

## **VOLUNTEER**

## Childcare Program(outreach) | Cognizant, Mumbai

07/2019-01/2020

- Helped students with basic concepts of Maths.
- Helped them regarding money management for future.
- School cleaning with team members.

## Sales associate at General Nutrition company | Toronto

09/2023-present

- Working as a GNC nutrition coach .
- Recommending best supplement regarding the goals.
- Creating sales records and shipments.